The crime that shocked a nation.
In Cold Blood is a crime, drama, thriller film directed by Richard Brooks.
After a botched robbery results in the brutal murder of a rural family, two drifters elude police, in the
end coming to terms with their own mortality and the repercussions of their vile atrocity.
Perry Smith, played by Robert Blake.
Richard 'Dick' Hickcock, played by Scott Wilson.
Alvin Dewey, played by John Forsythe.
Jensen, played by Paul Stewart.
Harold Nye, played by Gerald S. O'Loughlin.
Mr. Hickock, played by Jeff Corey.
Truman Capote's In Cold Blood (usually just referred to as In Cold Blood) is a 1967 American neo-noir biographical crime
film written, produced and directed by Richard Brooks, based on Truman Capote's 1966 nonfiction novel.
It stars Robert Blake as Perry Smith and Scott Wilson as Richard "Dick"
Hickock, two men who murder a family of four in Holcomb, Kansas.
Although the film is largely faithful to the book, Brooks made some slight alterations, including
the inclusion of a fictional character, Jensen, a reporter (played by Paul Stewart).
The film was shot on location at sites where Smith and Hickock's crimes occurred, including the
real Clutter home where they robbed and murdered four members of the family.
In Cold Blood was released by Columbia Pictures on December 15, 1967.
It was both a commercial and critical success and was nominated for four Academy Awards,
including for Best Director and Best Adapted Screenplay, among other accolades.
In 2008, In Cold Blood was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of murder, true crime, farmer, gay theme, tragic.
The tone is intense and dark and emotional.